My dear friends, I
welcome you to this Divyansh Bheetar
YouTube channel and if you have
not yet subscribed to this channel, then
please subscribe and keep commenting, liking and
sharing and if you have
not pressed the bell icon, then please press it,
sir, from today I am going to start a series, the
jersey of which is related to current
affairs, so it is serious for us and it is related
to current affairs and
why did we think of starting this series,
it has two objects, the first
object is that in such a situation its
weightage because you are taking online examination,
in this its weightage
is increasing and the second object was that every day we will give
you some questions per day, we will be
able to provide current affairs,
okay now when I will discuss the questions, when
you see these questions,
you watch this video, then write the answers in the copy, then
draw this line in the middle, then make
a
metro line in the middle because sir,
along with these questions, I will tell you some miscellaneous facts
that are related to current affairs
What is its background and what will
I give you about the options as well, I will give you
information which is very important
for the examination, you think that there is a
question about love,
which you do not know at all where it is from, so
friends, the questions are related to the
miscellaneous section and all those
questions are related to the miscellaneous section,
so
what will happen with this, sir, through this series, you will prepare 22 portions, the
first
portion of yours will be prepared for current affairs,
and the second portion is sir, you will have a
lot of your miscellaneous effects, so when you
sit for the examination, when
you go for the examination, you will have a
school of knowledge and information
ready with you and anyway, if you are
not able to revise it, then
through the elimination method, you will reach the target to a great
extent,
okay,
and I had told you all this, this
is our responsibility.  And we are completely
dedicated to this that how we get you
35 plus marks in this exam
and it will happen it is very possible okay
and we will handle it okay but the
only thing I need from you is a
little time you watch the video
whatever improvement can be done you comment us in the comment box
okay just stay with us
Divyansh has also said this I would
also like to tell you we are only
asking for a long gown of your time
if you give us the time of these people
we guarantee your selection sir and
I have told earlier that Vyas told that
this kind of channel is not at all just for promotion
it is for eating and teaching as well as to
take you to your destination
okay so stay with us let's
start okay so the
first question which is in discussion recently is
what is Max Bupa your
Max Bupa now the question comes what is
Max Bupa so if we talk about Max Bupa then what is
Max Bupa health insurance what is
your health insurance it is very popular
If you have noticed that nowadays
as admissions are taking place, the condition of people is getting
worse, so what are people doing now, they have
started taking a lot of health insurance, so what is
Max Bupa, its fame is quite high, it can
come in the paper from nutrition, so right
now its MD and CEO, who is
Krishna Ram Charan, so sir, you remember who is Krishna and Ram Charan
of Max Bupa, questions can be asked on Max Bupa also,
your exam mission can
come, what is Max Bupa, how does Max Bupa
hang, so remember, Max Bupa is
related to health insurance,
what is it related to health insurance, it is
clear, the thing you need to remember is
Pooja, when was it formed and where is its headquarter,
just remember this much, Max Bupa is
related to it and its current MD and CEO is of
quality, so who is its MD-CEO,
who is Krishna Ramachandran, Krishna Ram, let's
clear the first question, we will
come to the second question, sir, a few second questions,
very important question  Yes, now another one has
come out, now which club was this, whose name was
your fan club's bass, Bamboo, who clicked,
your bamboo can click on the
book content, now you must be thinking, oh
call 21 pipes are sleeping, right now there is a long gown
move everywhere, all the complexes were held
through video conferencing, till this was done through
BBC, a conference was
organized through this, okay, in this conclave, the
provisions that were taken in this conclave, the
main discussion was also on this,
bamboo, bamboo means your bass, in
what type of use can we use it, from this side
we can use it as an economic product in many
ways,
so all these things were discussed,
and sir, now the question arises that
who represented India in Baskale,
for whom was it held,
Dr. Jitendra Singh represented India
in this, Dr.
Jitendra Singh represented India because this is the Ministry
of Development of North Eastern Region,
Ministry of Development of North East Region, in the
home of the North East Region  Ministry and
who is your minister for that,
now you must be understanding this and
North Eastern came
because 60% of the country's base is in
those North Eastern, 60% of the country's
production happens there,
your North Eastern is there, okay, so
what has the Minister of North East Ministry done in this, he has represented you, he has represented, he has done representation, it
is clear, now which
clip just happened
regarding representation in this, Jitendra Singh did it, why did
Jitendra Singh do it,
okay because what is the Ministry of
North East, he is your minister, okay
and why did North East go there,
what happens to 60% bamboo in North East,
your products, it is clear, let's
move on to the next question,
Salman, next question is that
recently an award was given, Young Career
Award Young Career Report, in which you were given an award for
your work in Nano Science and Technology,
what have you done in Nano Science and Technology, you were
given an award for Nano Technology.
Who got the Young Career Award?
Sourav Lauda got it. Sourav, okay,
you remember this a little bit. Okay, let's
come to the next portion. It is very
important. Recently, the
Exit app was launched by the government. Right now, you are seeing
what is happening, sir. Corbett Nozzle, okay,
people are down everywhere.
What should all the governments do with this? To deal with this, to
reduce the burden, something or the other is
needed. And today's time, subscription means
use of technology to
reach people through the use of technology. Subscribe, if not then we should subscribe to the app
whose name is school. Now,
people from other states who are
stuck in West Bengal can get a pass by using this app
only. Can they get a pass?
You must have also seen that a pass
campaign is going on everywhere. People can take it and say that
others can also get rid of it. So, let me
tell you the clear things.
In West Bengal, Kolkata, the
Chief Minister of West Bengal, Mamata
Banerjee has been appointed as the Governor of West Bengal.
According to your Dheer and Mamata Banerjee, Mamata
Banerjee  The party of Trinamool Congress Party
subscribe is associated with Mamata Banerjee's party in Bengal
Sir and this party is a national
party keep in mind what kind of party it is a
national party is it clear then
we come to the next question Sir just now an
award was given to Cancer Very Important
Award Mark Wahlberg Award
Mark Subscribe Award Dhruv Vikram
Award what is it related to so let me
tell you what is it
related to environment environment those who
work for environment and climate change are
given awards the first question you will be
asked that CPI(M) and subscribe and
work for climate change
those who work against climate are given this award is
clear first question is done
now the second question comes
who gives it so who gives it is
your shrinkage state it does it
yours gives it to those who do good work it
is written here okay let's
see for whom this award is
given in climate change father
remember that it is given for climate change
you don't have to remember anything else for
whom  For whom have you got it, what should
you do now? You have to remember anything. You just have to keep
one thing in mind.
This award is given for environment and climate change.
Who gives it? Suggests it. Who gives it?
Your Sudan? And the Abhiraj of Sudan,
who is your Prakr Gustav? Who is this
Carl Gustav? Okay, you can see
who are the second, third, fourth?
You don't need to remember the amount of the prize. How much
amount is given here is clear.
Now the question comes,
who got the award in 2020? The award in 2019. Add
all the above. Now
how can you remember such names? So first, I will tell you
who has been given the Josh to Recharge Nicholas,
from Job to Richard Nicholas. Now
a thought comes in the minds of many people that if they
change the name behind, if
they change the name in front of the level like this, then
everything will be fine. Sir, I had told you earlier also that
SSC exams are not made, they are set.
No one makes the exam question paper by keeping it on the copy. Okay, they have got it done and they come back. So,
you don't
worry about it at all.  Don't do it, you can use the resort, of
course you can, so you can just
talk about the first name.
Yes sir, let me tell you another fact
about Stockholm. It is
after Stockholm. Sir, the first environment committee was held in Stockholm
in 1972.
What happened to the first environment committee at that time? You remember by
whose name we know it as the Environment
Committee. Okay, the first
environment committee was held in Stockholm and in the same year, it was decided to
celebrate World Environment Day. It was decided to
celebrate World Environment Day. It is
clear that there is a text and you remember,
in Stockholm, in 1972, the maximum time was taken to
celebrate World Environment Day.
And it is a fact that at the same time, the
meaning of appointment is United
Nations Environment Programme. It means
United Nations Environment Programme was formed.
In 1972 and 1977, it was
said that the organization is trying to
conserve the environment and save the environment.  Okay,
where is the institute testing for this, so where is it in Nairobi,
where is it testing for this, you
can subscribe to it, it is very important, where is it in
Nairobi, where is the appointed question in Kenya, so
what has happened, no one
can meet physically, no
work can be done physically,
and which video judgment
platform was launched, that was launched in the
banking sector, when there is
exchange of money in the banking and finance sector, then
they have to do KYC,
what do they have to do, I mean, know your customer,
they have to do it, so
you should not have any problem in this, they will not have to call any
person physically to their office,
for that, they have to launch a
platform completely online,
how should you launch a platform,
launch an online platform,
what is its name, your video KYC in
judgment platform, now the question comes, who should
launch it, Sanjay Amiro is a company, in which
we should launch UNESCO,
who is its CEO,
Vishal Laxminagar, COO of Ram's College, whom should
Amiro launch, okay, which platform should be launched
Video KYC in pregnant
is clear that the next question comes
towards the next
question is who is your good friend Putin, who is
your good friend Putin's party, who is
your president, what is the
president of Russia, he has
just been awarded the Second World War medal, keep in mind the
Second World War medal, so
whom should Shahrukh honor, whom should Kim Jong-un honor, you know
Kim Jong Un and Kim
Jong, you already know Kim Jong, okay,
who doesn't know him, the news of his death
was very much spread, it is not known whether he is dead or
alive, there is still complete doubt about it,
so the capital of Russia
is Moscow, okay, who
is the president of Russia, there are friends, okay, the
currency used here is the Russian ruble, okay,
if we talk about the capital of North Korea,
what is the capital of North Korea, it is
Pyongyang, by the way, its correct name is People's
Democratic Republic of North Korea,
what is the name, what is the currency of People's Democratic Republic
of North Korea,
North  North Korea of ​​Korea
operates here and the dictator
here is Kim Jong Un, who is very famous,
you must be knowing him, coming to the next question,
now the next portion is very
important, now a campaign has been
launched, a program named Samudra
Setu, what is the name of your Samudra Setu, it is very
important, so Sir, what
is Samudra Setu Abhiyan, Samudra Setu Abhiyan,
who has launched it, the Indian Navy, and
for whom has the campaign been launched, to rescue the
people of India who are stranded in other countries, to rescue
them,
okay, who is running the campaign,
your Indian Navy is running it, okay, so
remember which busy Samudra Setu
program has been run by you, due to the quality,
regarding such quote 9, a
campaign is being run to rescue the people stranded in other countries,
by whom, by the Indian Navy, by
whom, by the Indian
Navy, it is clear that this answer
is wrong, in this you can also do it in Indian,
what can you do, Indian Navy, okay, let me
tell you a little more, Sir CISCE
What does IS mean? Your Central
Industrial Security Force,
which is the upper order of your big industries,
a police force was formed to protect them, what was its
name? When was CISF formed? 1969.
Your company, the police force was formed in 1969. It is clear. Let's
talk about DSE. Sunday
AP. DSC means Defence Position
Exposition Council, Defence Situation
Council. Now what is the answer to the difference question,
Sir, Sir, whatever number of plants there are, whatever number of
agreements you have, to
procure anything in defence, you have to
comment on the technology and knowledge competition.
Who looks after all these things? Your Distance
Education Council looks after DSE. When was this BSC
established in 2001? By
2001, the Kargil war was over, then
we would have felt a great need for this thing.
Okay, so you remember
when was your DSC established in 2001. Now let us
see about the current situation, what is the current situation?  How is Hindustan
Sir, Hindustan
's Hindustan Aeronautics Limited, how is
your Hindustan Aeronautics
Limited, sir, whose is yours, it is just
air defence of India, the
biggest institutions related to it in India,
it is the biggest institution in India,
okay,
where is your SQ in Bengaluru, where is
it active in Bengaluru, in 1968, your
Hindustan Aeronautics Limited was formed,
remember, it is the biggest institution
in the aerospace sector, okay,
when was it formed, in 1968, and where are you,
Bengaluru is clear,
we come to the next question, the next question is now
start this campaign, if you are on Facebook, then while
watching this, subscribe to India and India here,
you must have seen Shahrukh
Khan subscribe,
what kind of consult a virtual is this, here all those
people sitting at home are doing something or the
other with their skills, by
singing songs sung by singers, by
acting, what are you doing, you have
organized a consult virtual concert, through which they can
earn some money, will the money go down, and
where will this money be used then  Yours is to
fight 119, okay, so
who organized the Consult of India, then
Facebook is very
famous, you can be asked, okay,
we come to the next question, who
recently started the Safe Grandparents
Campaign, it is
important to start the Safe Grandparents
and Grandparents campaign, Kunwar, subscribe from your corner,
NITI Aayog has started a campaign, NITI Aayog has
started a campaign, what should one do with this, to
shrink the case, NITI Aayog has made it
clear, now let us
see a little about it, what is NITI Aayog, so there used to be a
Planning Commission, there used to be a
Planning Commission, after
abolishing it, we established it on
January 1, 2015, it was established on January 1, 2015, it is
clear, I will tell you about it in detail in one of my articles,
you must
subscribe, those who do four marks of examination, those who
do it completely,
subscribe if I then my  Turn on the mode,
56001 symptoms and it is of 20 minutes,
if I talk then mostly it is going to take 10, if
you do 10 * 20 then more and
more 5 to 6 hours, the fixed topic is getting over in five-six hours,
you should start a little bit of this type of
information, in Economics it will be
over in five hours, History, Modern
History of Medieval History and in these
districts, in total it may get over in 10 hours,
okay, so less than a day on that, so
if you waste even a little time here, then
all your topics
are ready and I guarantee it sir,
your weapon will not go outside this, I
guarantee it, okay, so this is NITI Aayog,
okay, start this campaign in it, there is
also a CSIR, maybe you must be knowing it
sir, what is your Central Industrial
Scientific Research, what is
your Central Industrial Scientific
Research, this is India's biggest organization,
which field's research
and development, which now scans,
you are from the 80s,
when was yours formed?  So when was the 19421 policy
made, 90 was clear, coming to the next question, yes
sir, now the next question is,
which state recently launched the Ayush Kavach app,
so I just told you that
everyone is launching such an app,
so by launching such an app,
farmers are launching it in your Uttar Pradesh,
you know the capital of Uttar Pradesh
is Lucknow, you all
know very well the CM Yogi Adityanath and the Governor is
Anandiben Patel, who is your Anandiben
Patel, is that right,
coming to the next question, sir, what just happened, there will be a central minister,
what will happen to the central minister, if you die, then
who is he, your Dalit
Ajilmalai, who is your Dalit Ajilmalai, one question is
important because you are asked to
tell me Dalit Taaji Malai because the name is also
not very common, to which field is Dalit Taaji Malai
related, 45 fields will be given to you
in the paper, in this one will be politician,
one will be your artist, one will be music
director, four options of this type will be made, so
you will be asked  It will be said that tell me
an incident from which field, so you have to
tell here which field you are from, are you a
politician, are you a politician,
former Union Minister in the BJP government, that when your
government was of BJP government,
okay, then you were the Health Minister in 1998,
okay, it is clear, you have understood the thing,
okay, so that's all for today,
in the next section, along with the
current affairs, you will have a lot of questions,
this portion of your missions will also be
ready,
thank you so much.